adknowledge.com 2004-12-30

# privacy.adknowledge.com

THE ADNOWLEDGE PRIVACY POLICY MAY CHANGE FROM TIME TO TIME.

PLEASE CHECK BACK FREQUENTLY FOR UPDATES.

Effective as of December 23, 2004

This privacy policy ("Policy") describes how personally identifiable information you voluntarily provide, authorize to be released, or which is publicly available may be obtained and used by Adknowledge, Inc. ("Adknowledge") or an affiliated party. Adknowledge is a technology company that provides advertisements to consumers, directly as well as through third party Websites, software programs and email databases (together, these third party sources are referenced hereafter as "Publishers"). As used herein, "online" means using the Internet, including Websites and related technologies and "offline" means methods other than online, including in person, via postal mail, telephone and similar means. This Policy does not apply to the practices of Publishers or other companies that Adknowledge does not own or control or to people that Adknowledge does not employ or manage. 

1\. _Collection of Information_. 

1.1 _Subscription or Survey Information_. Adknowledge collects information from you when you voluntarily provide it to Adknowledge or one of its Publishers (for example, by signing up for an email newsletter or through a co-registration offer on a survey), or by others means of online or offline surveys, order forms, or registration pages operated by third parties (collectively, a "User Form"). In a User Form, Adknowledge or a third party may offer you incentives in exchange for providing information about yourself such as name, email address, street address, zip code, telephone numbers, birth date, gender, salary range, education and marital status, occupation, employment information, and personal and online interests (together, "User Information"). Completing the Surveys is voluntary and you are under no obligation to provide User Information. 

1.2 _Vendor List Information_. Adknowledge may obtain information about you after you provide information to a third party and you permit that party (the "Seller") to share the information, which Adknowledge subsequently purchases, licenses, or otherwise lawfully acquires. Such information may include, but is not limited to, your name, street address, zip code, telephone numbers, birth date, gender, salary range, education, marital status, occupation, industry of employment, personal and online interests, and other information which you provided to the Seller (together, "Vendor List Information"). When acquiring Vendor List Information, Adknowledge requires assurances from the Seller that the Seller has a right to transfer the Vendor List Information to Adknowledge and that the Adknowledge may lawfully use the Vendor List Information to transmit offers from advertisers. 

1.3 User Behaviors Collected with Cookies, Web beacons, and Other Information . Adknowledge uses cookie and web beacon technology to associate certain Internet-related information about you, such as your IP address, with certain of your online behaviors, such as opening or clicking on a particular online advertisement. Additionally, Adknowledge may use other new and evolving sources of information and information gathering in the future (together, "Technology Information"). 

(a) Cookies. A cookie is a small amount of data stored on the hard drive of your computer that allows Adknowledge to identify your IP address with corresponding information in Adknowledge's database. Adknowledge may use cookies to track individual responses or views of advertisements. You may read more about cookies at www.cookiecentral.com. 

(b) Web beacons. A web beacon is programming code used to display an image on a web page and can also transfer an individual's user identification to a database and associate the individual with previously acquired information about the individual. Web beacons enable Adknowledge to track certain Web sites you visit or advertisements you view online. Web beacons help determine products or services in which you may be interested and help track online behaviors for marketing purposes. More information about web beacons is available at http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/W/Web_beacon.html. 

(c) Where Technology Information is Collected. Technology Information is collected directly from Adknowledge advertisements or indirectly through Publishers that Adknowledge contracts with to display advertisements. Such advertisements will usually be displayed within one of the following advertising vehicles: 

> _Websites_. Adknowledge may set a cookie on your computer when you view advertisements delivered on Publisher Websites. After a cookie is set, Adknowledge may track how you interact with the advertisement and the Publisher Website (for example, registering, purchasing, browsing, etc.). 
> 
> _Software Programs_. Similar to Websites, Adknowledge displays banner advertisements in software programs that you may use. 
> 
> _Email Databases_. Adknowledge may track your interaction with email advertisements sent to you on behalf of Publishers or partner Websites (for example, when you register, purchase, or browse in response to such email). 

1.4 _Outside Information_. Adknowledge may lawfully receive information about you from third parties, such as information located in public databases ("Outside Information"). 

1.5 _No Information Collected from Children_. Adknowledge does not collect any personal information about children under the age of 13. If Adknowledge is notified it has personal information about a child under the age of 13, that information will be promptly deleted from our database. Adknowledge designed this policy in order to with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA"). 

1.6 _Individual Information_. As used herein, Individual Information means Survey Information, Vendor List Information, Technology Information, Outside Information, and any other information Adknowledge lawfully obtains about you. 

2\. _Use of Individual Information and User Data_. 

2.1 _Discretion to Use Information_. Adknowledge does not rent, sell or share your Individual Information to any third party without giving you notice of our intent to do so and allowing you the option to remove yourself from such transaction; however, we may share information with trusted Publishers under confidentiality agreements. These Publishers may use your Individual Information to better target advertisements to you; they do not have any right to sell, rent or share your Individual Information unless you have granted them such right. Adknowledge may maintain its own email list for any lawful purpose. If you wish to end your email subscription with us or one of our Publishers, you may follow the instructions at the end of each email message to unsubscribe or follow the instructions detailed at Section 4 below. 

2.2 _Targeted Advertising_. Adknowledge uses Individual Information to target advertising more effectively. When an individual is online, Adknowledge uses Technology Information to associate an individual with their Individual Information and Adknowledge attempts to show advertising for products and services to which the person may respond. Adknowledge may use information collected from a response to one type of advertising for targeting advertisements through a different venue. For example, Adknowledge may notice that you responded to a baseball banner advertisement and use that response to deliver a baseball advertisement to you via email. 

2.3 _Legal Process_. Adknowledge may disclose Individual Information to respond to subpoenas, court orders and other legal process as required by law. 

2.4 _Summary Data_. Adknowledge may sell or transfer non-individualized information, such as summary or aggregated anonymous information about all persons or sub-groups of persons. 

2.5 _Storage of Individual Information_. Adknowledge stores Individual Information in a database on Adknowledge computers. These computers have security measures, such as a firewall, to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under Adknowledge's control. Adknowledge also maintains physical and procedural safeguards to protect Individual Information. Notwithstanding such measures, Adknowledge cannot guarantee that its security measures will prevent these computers from being illegally accessed and the Individual Information on them stolen or altered. 

3\. _Privacy Practices of Third Parties_. 

3.1 _Advertiser cookies and web beacons_. Publishers who place advertisements on the Internet may use their own cookies, web beacons and other technology to collect information about you. Adknowledge does not control Publishers' use of such technology. 

3.2 _Links_. The Publishers' Websites and email messages transmitted by Adknowledge on its own behalf or on behalf of Publishers may contain hypertext links to the Websites of third parties. Adknowledge is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other Websites. 

3.3 _Affiliated Companies that are not Publishers_. Adknowledge may disclose, transfer and sell Individual Information to entities affiliated with Adknowledge in Adknowledge's discretion. 

4\. _HOW YOU MAY EXERCISE YOUR PRIVACY RIGHTS AND UNSUBSCRIBE_. 

> _Websites_. To prevent the display of Publisher or Adknowledge advertising on a Website, for example, banner advertisements, do not visit the Website. To only prevent Adknowledge from tracking your behavior on a Website, turn off cookies from that Website and do not click on the advertisement. 
> 
> _Email Databases_. To unsubscribe from Adknowledge or Publisher email lists, click the link included in the footer of any message delivered by Adknowledge or a Publisher and follow the instructions provided. You may also unsubscribe by visiting Adknowledge's homepage, [www.adknowledge.com](http://www.adknowledge.com/), clicking on "Contact Us" and requesting to unsubscribe; you may also visit [http://privacy.adknowledge.com](http://privacy.adknowledge.com/) and click on "Unsubscribe." 
> 
> Please read the privacy policy for Adknowledge and its Publishers to understand how your Individual Information may be used after you unsubscribe. Adknowledge has a policy of not disclosing Individual Information to a third party after you have unsubscribed from Adknowledge's email lists. 
> 
> _Software Programs_. To prevent software programs from displaying advertisements on your computer, uninstall the Software Program provided by an Adknowledge Publisher by following the instructions included in the privacy policy at the time of installation. Software Programs should include an option to uninstall in the "Add/Remove Programs" section of the Windows® operating system, or by visiting the file director of the installed program and running an uninstaller executable. 

5\. _More Information_. For more information about protecting your privacy, you may wish to visit [privacy.adknowledge.com](http://privacy.adknowledge.com/), [www.netcoalition.com](http://www.netcoalition.com/), and [www.privacyalliance.org](http://www.privacyalliance.org/). Adknowledge reserves the right to update this Policy at any time by republishing it to this Website with a new effective date. If you have questions about this Policy, please contact us at [privacy@adknowledge.com](mailto:privacy@adknowledge.com?Subject=Questions%20about%20Adknowledge%20Privacy%20Policy) or write to us at: 

Adknowledge, Inc.  
Attn: Privacy Officer  
4600 Madison Ave., 5th Floor  
Kansas City, MO 64112  

Copyright 2004 Adknowledge, Inc. All rights reserved.   
  
All content copyright © 2004 Adknowledge, Inc. All rights reserved.
